<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 07:51:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nominate PrestaShop! in the 2016 Critics’ Choice CMS Awards</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nominate-prestashop-2016-critics-choice-cms-awards/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nominate-prestashop-2016-critics-choice-cms-awards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 08:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=22009</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>We are once again running for the Critics’ Choice CMS Awards. Please help us get nominated in the categories: Best Open Source CMS and Best eCommerce Software Nominations close on September first, so go here to lend your support. There is no time to lose. Please nominate us in the following two categories: Best Open [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nominate-prestashop-2016-critics-choice-cms-awards/">Nominate PrestaShop! in the 2016 Critics’ Choice CMS Awards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are once again running for the Critics’ Choice CMS Awards.</p>
<p>Please help us get nominated in the categories: Best Open Source CMS and Best eCommerce Software Nominations close on September first, so go here to lend your support. There is no time to lose.</p>
<p><span id="more-22009"></span></p>
<p>Please nominate us in the following two categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>Best Open Source CMS</li>
<li>Best eCommerce Software</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a class="btn btn-sucess" style="background-color: #2f2f2f; border: 1px solid #191717; border-bottom: 3px solid #292727; margin: 20px 0 0; color: #fff;" href="https://goo.gl/Id19gi" target="_blank"><i class="fa fa-ticket"></i>   Submit Your Nomination</a></p>
<p>We really appreciate your support! Help us spread the word by using the social sharing icons at the bottom of this blog post. We’ll keep you posted on the results!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nominate-prestashop-2016-critics-choice-cms-awards/">Nominate PrestaShop! in the 2016 Critics’ Choice CMS Awards</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nominate-prestashop-2016-critics-choice-cms-awards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP) &amp; How Can It Help My Website?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/accelerated-mobile-pages-amp-can-help-website/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/accelerated-mobile-pages-amp-can-help-website/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 07:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21895</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Since Google launched Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP), an open source initiative, the world has quickly adapted to it. Considered to speed up mobile browsing, the project has had the cooperation of many big names in the technology industry. But what is AMP, how does it affect your SEO efforts and what benefits can your website [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/accelerated-mobile-pages-amp-can-help-website/">What is Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP) &amp; How Can It Help My Website?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since Google launched Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP), an open source initiative, the world has quickly adapted to it. Considered to speed up mobile browsing, the project has had the cooperation of many big names in the technology industry.</p>
<p><span id="more-21895"></span></p>
<p>But what is AMP, how does it affect your SEO efforts and what benefits can your website reap from it? Here’s the whole story.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/08/1-amp.jpg" alt="1 amp" width="800" height="400" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-22006" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #078ac0">What is AMP?</span></h2>
<p>Accelerated Mobile Pages or AMP is an Open-source coding standard that is developed to allow web pages on mobile phones to load faster. AMP enables publishers to take heavy and clunky web pages and streamline them.</p>
<p>To effectively run these AMP sites, a thin version of HTML is included rather than the bulky website version. This slim line of code allows sites to load faster in smaller spaces, such as your smartphones.</p>
<p>Features of an AMP website include;</p>
<ul>
<li>Use of CSS and HTML is streamlined, with the size of inline CSS in less than 50kb.</li>
<li>Includes Image Lazy Load, which means images appear only when you scroll down.</li>
<li>Ads and Analytics are accepted on AMP, just like regular web pages.</li>
<li>No Javascript should be used.</li>
<li>AMP sites must be validated with the AMP Validator which comes bundled with the AMP JS Library.</li>
<li>Custom fonts must be specially loaded, and image height and width must be declared.</li>
<li>Forms are not allowed.</li>
<li><span style="line-height: 1.5">Videos can be included by using AMP approved extensions. </span></li>
</ul>
<p>All these restrictions ensure quicker loading times and will eliminate the frustration of waiting for a long time to access content.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #078ac0">What are the benefits of AMP?</span></h2>
<ul>
<li>Faster Load Times</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">By far, the greatest advantage of Accelerated Mobile Pages is quick loading web pages. </span></p>
<p>Have you ever tried to access content from your smartphone? Then, you would understand the long wait you have to endure due to the slow loading speeds. With most users on a slow-internet pack, the speed offered is simply not enough to access information on-the-go.</p>
<p>However, with AMP, you can access content faster. According to Google, AMP web pages load 15-85% faster than the non-AMP websites. With faster loading sites, you give your users a better experience. If the users have quick access to information, they will most certainly stay on your website longer.</p>
<ul>
<li>SEO Benefits:</li>
</ul>
<p>It is pretty evident that the future is mobile, and Google is an advocate of this idea too. So if your website is mobile-friendly, Google caches these sites quicker thus improving your ranking. Also, the longer a user stays on your page, the better your page ranking gets.</p>
<p>The importance of AMP pages cannot be emphasized more than with Google’s introduction of the AMP page carousel that appears on the first page of mobile search results. The carousel features articles that are related to the query. It includes an image with the article heading. The kind of content marketing you’d receive is huge.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21898" alt="2 amp" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/2-amp.png" width="352" height="651" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><span style="color: #078ac0">Who can use AMP pages?</span></h2>
<p>Although, Accelerated Mobile Pages are great, is it worth the time and effort? Not for everyone.</p>
<p>Accelerated Mobile pages are useful for sites that publish blog content, news articles or any other kind of content. However, if you convert your products or service page into AMP, you’ll lose the chance to impress your visitors with gorgeous websites, due to the slim HTML code required for AMP mobile pages.</p>
<p>So rather than turning your entire website into AMP, focus on converting your blog section or news feed into AMP. With lightning fast loading on your blog section, users will receive the information they need quickly thus improving your ranking.</p>
<p>If you are a content marketer or a publishing website releasing fresh content frequently, then AMP will be a lucrative tool for increasing your search engine ranking.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #078ac0">Get started with AMP</span></h2>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-21924" alt="amp" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/amp.png" width="869" height="489" /></p>
<p>If you have a WordPress site, then there’s a 5-minute process for integrating AMP. Use the following plug-ins.</p>
<ul>
<li>AMP WordPress by Automattic</li>
<li>Yoast SEO</li>
</ul>
<p>If your website is not WordPress-based, then you’ll have to go to the AMP website and learn how to integrate it by hard-coding it.</p>
<p>Once you do integrate your AMP, be patient. Your content will not immediately appear in search results. Google will take at least a few days to crawl these new pages. It can be a relatively slow process, especially when it comes to already existing content.</p>
<p>AMP is a free open source framework offering lucrative opportunities for you to build your site ranking and search engine results. Don’t lose up on this opportunity to give your users a faster mobile experience with Accelerated Mobile Pages.</p>
<p>Will you be implementing AMP for you blog and content pages? Share your thoughts in the comments below.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>About the author:</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignleft" alt="Logo" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/Logo.jpg" width="258" height="90" />SHAMLATECH is a Global Enterprise Service Agency serving happy clients over the past 8 years in the industry. The services include web and eCommerce development, Mobile application development and Digital Marketing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/accelerated-mobile-pages-amp-can-help-website/">What is Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP) &amp; How Can It Help My Website?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/accelerated-mobile-pages-amp-can-help-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Golden October with Amazon Payments</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/golden-october-amazon-payments/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/golden-october-amazon-payments/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 12:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21988</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Don’t miss this golden opportunity to get started with Amazon Payments: Sow the seeds to help grow your business by 22 September 2016 and earn up to 3 months without service fees*. Offer Amazon Payments to your customers for a trusted, fast, and secure way to pay. Make it predictably simple for more than 300 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/golden-october-amazon-payments/">Golden October with Amazon Payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Don’t miss this golden opportunity to get started with Amazon Payments: Sow the seeds to help grow your business by 22 September 2016 and earn up to 3 months without service fees*.</p>
<p><span id="more-21988"></span></p>
<p>Offer Amazon Payments to your customers for a trusted, fast, and secure way to pay. Make it predictably simple for more than 300 million Amazon customers to buy from your site, and Amazon Payments can help you:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increase conversions</li>
<li>Acquire new customers</li>
<li>Build customer loyalty</li>
<li>Reduce fraud</li>
</ul>
<p>This could be the best 4th quarter you’ve ever had.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a class="btn btn-sucess" style="background-color: #2f2f2f; border: 1px solid #191717; border-bottom: 3px solid #292727; margin: 20px 0 0; color: #fff;" href="https://go.amazonservices.com/GO_UK.html?ld=SPEXUKAPA-GO-BL-PS" target="_blank"><i class="fa fa-ticket"></i>   Register now</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/golden-october-amazon-payments/">Golden October with Amazon Payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/golden-october-amazon-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 smart competitive pricing tactics for eCommerce companies – part 2/2</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-22/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-22/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 07:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21977</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In part 1 of our 6 smart competitive pricing tactics, we shared 3 ways to price your products competitively: keep your eyes on costs, never undervalue your products, and compete for pricing at the brand or category level. Today we’ll share the next three competitive pricing tactics. 4 &#8211; Analyze your competitor’s historical pricing trends [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-22/">6 smart competitive pricing tactics for eCommerce companies – part 2/2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In part 1 of our 6 smart competitive pricing tactics, we shared 3 ways to price your products competitively: keep your eyes on costs, never undervalue your products, and compete for pricing at the brand or category level. Today we’ll share the next three competitive pricing tactics.</p>
<p><span id="more-21977"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e;">4 &#8211; Analyze your competitor’s historical pricing trends to detect sales like weekend discounts or nighttime flash sales</span></h2>
<p>(**Here’s 1-3 of this article.)<br />
Shopping occurs mainly in the present tense&#8211;it’s a matter of “now”. However, the same is not true of pricing. Most companies have <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_pricing" target="_blank">time-based pricing strategies</a> or <a href="https://blog.prisync.com/implementing-an-effective-discount-strategy/" target="_blank">discounting strategies</a>. Some of them have public campaigns for their weekend sales, and some of them built a loyal shopper base for their late-night discount frenzy.</p>
<p>Gaining insight into such trends and acting competitively on them is as vital as being competitive at the product level.</p>
<p>This is because these trends or campaigns go beyond offering a simple discount; they are about building a loyal customer base.</p>
<p>Therefore, eCommerce companies should also monitor and analyze the historical pricing trends of their competitors while closely tracking actual prices.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21979" alt="image1" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/image1.jpg" width="1300" height="867" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e;">5 &#8211; Focus on your competitors’ out-of-stock products</span></h2>
<p>Prices matter, but only as long as a company can deliver the product.<br />
Online shoppers consider product availability and prices at the same time. If a product isn’t available, the shopper is likely to make the purchase elsewhere. It works similar to how an expensive product works in the minds of an online shopper. It fails to grab the attention of the shopper and forces it to find another option.</p>
<p>This represents an opportunity for eCommerce companies. You can consider the stock availabilities of your competitors as a solid pricing opportunity.</p>
<p>When the competition is out of stock for a tight-margin product it means that shoppers do not have many choices, so their willingness to pay more will be higher. Therefore, the eCommerce company with competitive advantage and stock availability gets the potential advantage in pricing. With the right technology, companies can gain insights on their competitors’ stock availabilities and prices, then implement this strategy, on the spot.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e;">6 &#8211; Negotiate better deals with suppliers with data </span></h2>
<p>Data is a solid weapon when it comes to business negotiations. It’s a very objective way of presenting an argument.</p>
<p>No one can dispute data and suppliers to <a href="https://blog.prisync.com/tips-supplier-relationships-in-ecommerce/" target="_blank">eCommerce companies</a> are no exception.<br />
It’s common to see eCommerce companies complain to their suppliers about the prices they see over at their competitors for certain products that they also carry in their assortments. Just mentioning this to your supplier won’t get you very far. But when this negotiation is handled in a structured format with clear data demonstrating a supplier-affected disadvantage for that eCommerce company, things may flow in a different direction. Providing hard evidence can bring further discounts or deals.</p>
<p>In short, you can act smart and show that you know what’s really going on between your suppliers and competitors, and confidently demand the best deal for yourself.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e;">Conclusion</span></h2>
<p>Competitive pricing intelligence is a multi-dimensional analysis should not be regarded as only monitoring product prices vs. competitors.</p>
<p>Even though such monitoring offers significant sales and a profit boost, that should not be considered enough. Going further by implementing the pricing strategies mentioned above can help eCommerce companies of all sizes further outsmart their competitors in today’s wildly competitive eCommerce market.</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>About the Author</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-21929" alt="6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_4" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_4.png" width="144" height="177" />Burc Tanir is an SMB-loving, eCommerce evangelist and the CEO of Prisync.com, the competitor price tracking software, already serving companies from more than 40 countries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-22/">6 smart competitive pricing tactics for eCommerce companies – part 2/2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-commerce delivery: Why is it essential to provide an optimal logistic experience on your web shop</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-commerce-delivery-essential-provide-optimal-logistic-experience-web-shop/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-commerce-delivery-essential-provide-optimal-logistic-experience-web-shop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 07:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21950</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Delivery Delivery is becoming increasingly important for online shoppers. These days, many web shops are focusing on delivering orders as fast as possible, but they often do not offer enough options. A European study (MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015) with 3,000 online shoppers, aged 18 to 65, indicated that the logistic experience is key in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-commerce-delivery-essential-provide-optimal-logistic-experience-web-shop/">E-commerce delivery: Why is it essential to provide an optimal logistic experience on your web shop</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2><span style="color: #d40029">Delivery</span></h2>
<p><strong>Delivery</strong> is becoming increasingly <strong>important</strong> for online shoppers. These days, many web shops are focusing on delivering orders as fast as possible, but they often do not offer enough options. A <strong>European study</strong> <em>(MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015)</em> with 3,000 online shoppers, aged 18 to 65, indicated that the <strong>logistic experience</strong> is key in the online buying process. No less than 49% of the consumers is willing to pay more for their purchases if they can select various delivery methods.</p>
<p><span id="more-21950"></span></p>
<p>For an increasing number of customers, <strong>choosing the delivery time and location</strong> is an important factor alongside the <strong>delivery speed</strong>. Customers do not always want to receive their order <strong>as soon as possible</strong>, but they do want to choose a <strong>delivery</strong> where <strong>they can receive the parcel themselves</strong>. For instance, online shoppers often choose delivery in a <strong>collection point</strong> so they can decide when to <strong>pick up the parcel</strong>: after work, during lunch break or even in the weekend.</p>
<div id="attachment_21963" style="width: 905px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-21963" alt="Source: MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/PourquoiExperienceLogistiqueImportante11.png" width="895" height="389" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015</p></div>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">Offering a parcel in a collection point is a great service towards your customers, but it also slightly goes against the </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">comfort of online shopping</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">. The solution is therefore offering several options. Enable your customers to choose their </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">own delivery time or location</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">. Do they want to receive the parcel </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">during the day</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">, </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">in the evening</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5"> or on a </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">Saturday</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">? Do they prefer </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">home delivery</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">, delivery </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">at work</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5"> or at a </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">collection point</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">? Online shoppers want to </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">choose</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5"> where and when they receive their order. To have a choice in the delivery gives the customers control. Control of their own freedom. Offering your customers </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">choice</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">, </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">speed</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5"> and </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">convenience</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5"> in the delivery will increase the </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">purchase probability</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">.</span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #d40029">Online flexibility</span></h2>
<div id="attachment_21964" style="width: 552px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-21964 " alt="Source: The most popular new delivery methods via the DHL Parcel Intervention portal – Oct ‘15-Feb ’16" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/PourquoiExperienceLogistiqueImportante21.png" width="542" height="409" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: The most popular new delivery methods via the<br />DHL Parcel Intervention portal – Oct ‘15-Feb ’16</p></div>
<p>Our <strong>busy schedules</strong> sometimes prevent us from being at home at the chosen delivery time. This is why you should give your customers more options by enabling them to <strong>intervene in case of a first missed delivery</strong>. If your customer is not at home when the courier visits, he/she can plan a new delivery moment via an online intervention tool on another day or at a different collection point. An <strong>intervention function</strong> not only offers your customers a <strong>flexible service</strong>, it also contributes to a <strong>sustainable process</strong>: guaranteed successful delivery!</p>
<p>When we look at the trends in the <strong>DHL intervention portal</strong>, it strikes us that when the recipient is not home during the first delivery attempt, people tend to opt for delivery at a <strong>different DHL Parcel collection point</strong> than initially planned. In addition, the trends of our intervention tool also indicate that all other available delivery options are also significantly important. These options give the customer a sense of <strong>freedom</strong>, <strong>flexibility</strong> and indicate <strong>professionalism</strong> of the sender.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d40029">Return solutions</span></h2>
<div id="attachment_21965" style="width: 585px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img class="size-full wp-image-21965 " alt="Source: Consumers who purchased articles online, knowing that they will (partly) return them (according to age) - MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/PourquoiExperienceLogistiqueImportante31.png" width="575" height="408" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: Consumers who purchased articles online, knowing that they will (partly) return them (according to age) &#8211; MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015</p></div>
<p>Apart from various delivery methods, the <strong>return solutions</strong> are also of high importance. While returning was originally important for consumers after buying, it now plays a crucial role in the <strong>purchase decision</strong> itself. As well as the delivery methods, the return options also influence the consumer when choosing a specific web shop. In addition, an increasing number of consumers make an online purchase with the <strong>intention of returning part of the purchases</strong>. Just as in fitting rooms, the consumer wants to try on several articles in various sizes and colours in order to make the right decision later on.</p>
<p>By offering your customers simple return solutions, you combine the <strong>convenience of online shopping</strong> with the <strong>freedom</strong> to make the right decision. Big players such as Zalando and bol.com are focusing on <strong>free and user-friendly</strong> returns. You too can offer your customers several return services. At DHL Parcel we can support your web shop in offering the following options: the customer requests a return label via <strong>your customer service</strong>, creates an <strong>online return label</strong> him/herself or uses the return label that is already <strong>in the box</strong>. With this return label, the customer can return the order via one of <strong>our DHL Parcelshops</strong>. With the <strong>biggest network of collection points</strong> in Belgium, DHL Parcel is always close to you and your customer.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #d40029">The key to success</span></h2>
<p><strong>The trend has definitely been set</strong>: those who want to be successful –as the leading web shops such as Bol.com and Amazon- need to <strong>expand their delivery options</strong>. However, is it also possible for a small web shop to offer this type of service? Yes, because the world of logistics is always evolving and will need to continuously offer improvements and <strong>innovative solutions</strong> to optimise the logistics experience of the consumer. Solutions that can provide an upgrade in service for the big players as well as for <strong>small start-up web shops</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_21966" style="width: 906px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-21966" alt="Source: MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/PourquoiExperienceLogistiqueImportante41.png" width="896" height="391" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Source: MetaPack “Flexible delivery options” 2015</p></div>
<p><span style="line-height: 1.5">It is safe to say that many consumers find where, when and how their parcel arrives remarkably more important than the price. </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">The delivery time, speed, location </strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">and the</span><strong style="line-height: 1.5"> return solutions</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5"> are the major motivators for a customer in choosing a specific web shop. Provide flexibility by choosing a logistics partner who is close to your customers and offers a wide </span><strong style="line-height: 1.5">range of delivery methods and return solutions</strong><span style="line-height: 1.5">. With the right offer of brands or products and an optimal logistics experience, you are at the start of a success story!</span></p>
<p>As <strong>official partner</strong> of PrestaShop, we at DHL Parcel want to help you write your success story. Click to download our <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/22138-dhl-parcel-belux.html" target="_blank">free shipping module</a>, request an <strong>account number</strong> and ship your parcels <strong>fast and easy</strong> with DHL Parcel.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-commerce-delivery-essential-provide-optimal-logistic-experience-web-shop/">E-commerce delivery: Why is it essential to provide an optimal logistic experience on your web shop</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-commerce-delivery-essential-provide-optimal-logistic-experience-web-shop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 smart competitive pricing tactics for eCommerce companies – part 1/2</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-12/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-12/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 07:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21927</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Competitive eCommerce pricing is not just price-matching or undercutting competitor prices. By using the right competitive intelligence technology, eCommerce companies can go way beyond that and competitively price in a more analytical and profitable way. I’ll show you how you can do just that by focusing on some often-neglected business scenarios that occur in eCommerce. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-12/">6 smart competitive pricing tactics for eCommerce companies – part 1/2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Competitive eCommerce pricing is not just price-matching or undercutting competitor prices.</strong></p>
<p>By using the right competitive intelligence technology, eCommerce companies can go way beyond that and competitively price in a more analytical and profitable way. I’ll show you how you can do just that by focusing on some often-neglected business scenarios that occur in eCommerce.</p>
<p><span id="more-21927"></span></p>
<p>Today, I’m sharing 6 business cases that prove eCommerce companies of all sizes can address and outsmart their competition with competitive pricing tactics. You won’t have to undercut prices and give away profit margins. I’ll teach you how you can act smart and fast by relying on <a href="https://prisync.com" target="_blank">automated competitor price monitoring technologies</a>.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21930" alt="6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_2" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_2.png" width="975" height="732" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e">1- Stay competitive while remaining profitable</span></h2>
<p>No eCommerce business company can survive by ignoring <a href="https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-standard-operating-costs-for-running-an-e-commerce-website" target="_blank">costs</a> and focusing solely on their competition. For all eCommerce companies, competitor pricing and product costs are conflicting forces that both impact product prices. Profitability should be a goal for eCommerce companies of all sizes, and to achieve that, eCommerce companies should always keep an eye on <a href="http://www.ecorner.com.au/FAQs-Questions-Ideas-Centre/Costs-Issues-Starting-An-eCommerce-Online-Business#.V17PYeZ96Rs" target="_blank">their costs</a>. <span style="text-decoration: underline">This is especially true when</span> you’re adjusting prices competitively against competitors.</p>
<p>Instead of undercutting the competition’s prices at every chance &#8211; no matter the cost &#8211; eCommerce companies should analyze their costs to achieve enduring and sustainable competitiveness.</p>
<p>When your prices are uncompetitive compared to the market average, you can fix this not just by lowering the price, but more importantly, trying to figure out ways to cut <strong>costs further up the chain</strong>. Only once you’ve lowered your own costs should you offer further discounts or lower prices for customers.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e">2 &#8211; Never undervalue your products and actively identify price increase opportunities </span></h2>
<p>Even if you can offer your products at a very competitive price compared to your competitors, your prices might be too competitive.</p>
<p>You low prices will draw shopper attention, which will bring in potential customers. But how low do you go then? If the customer’s deal-breaker was finding the best deal online, why not price your product at the max of the minimums? In other words, consider raising your price until it is almost priced at the second cheapest competitor, yet remains well below that.</p>
<p>In <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/top-5-tips-for-price-comparison-sites/" target="_blank">shopping comparison engines</a>, and in the minds of online shoppers, these price increases doesn’t make a difference. However, it will bring increased profit margins that lift up the balance sheet. Best of all, this price increase will not cost your company anything.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-21931" alt="6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_3" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_3.png" width="975" height="684" /></p>
<h2><span style="color: #3d698e">3- Study your competitor’s category and brand level pricing strategies</span></h2>
<p>In most cases, eCommerce prices are driven by category or brand level decisions. This may be due to budgeting operations within a company, or supplier deals in place for specific brands etc. When we consider this fact, solely focusing on competitor product price monitoring and micro-managing product prices feel a little dull.</p>
<p>With the right technologies, eCommerce companies can gain brand and category level pricing insights into their competitors. Aggregation is the method to look to here, i.e. grouping products under a certain brand or category together, and calculating their overall price performance for each site. Calculating an index value for the aggregated level (a category or brand) will give you an idea about how a company is performing pricing-wise for that particular brand and category vs. its competitors.</p>
<p>Such analysis may reveal which competitors have significant pricing advantages in which brands/categories, and which are lacking. ECommerce companies can act upon those comparative results and adjust pricing levels based on overall category and brand management strategies.</p>
<p>Want to learn more about competitive pricing tactics? Check out part 2 of this article.</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>About the Author</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-21929" alt="6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_4" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/07/6SmartCompetitivePricingTactics_4.png" width="144" height="177" />Burc Tanir is an SMB-loving, eCommerce evangelist and the CEO of Prisync.com, the competitor price tracking software, already serving companies from more than 40 countries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-12/">6 smart competitive pricing tactics for eCommerce companies – part 1/2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-smart-competitive-pricing-tactics-ecommerce-companies-part-12/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Small business guide to home rule and sales tax</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/small-business-guide-home-rule-sales-tax/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/small-business-guide-home-rule-sales-tax/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 08:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21879</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As a small business, collecting sales taxes can cost you time and money. But the consequences of not doing sales taxes right can be even worse. Dealing with “home rule” states can make things even trickier because those states allow local communities to set and process sales taxes themselves. It’s important to be aware of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/small-business-guide-home-rule-sales-tax/">The Small business guide to home rule and sales tax</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a small business, collecting sales taxes can cost you time and money. But the consequences of not doing sales taxes right can be even worse. Dealing with “<a href="https://www.avalara.com/blog/2015/11/02/sales-tax-q-a-home-rule-states/" target="_blank">home rule</a>” states can make things even trickier because those states allow local communities to set and process sales taxes themselves. It’s important to be aware of home rule sales tax issues to avoid potential pitfalls.</p>
<p><span id="more-21879"></span></p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">What is home rule?</span></h2>
<p>In general, home rule states allow local governments the authority to administer something differently than state law does. This can cover a lot of areas of government, including sales tax, and, in fact, 38 states allow local jurisdictions to impose their own sales taxes. In most of these states, localities must follow state guidelines in levying sales taxes, and sales taxes are collected on their behalf by the state.</p>
<p>However, there are a few states where local jurisdictions not only have the power to levy taxes but also have authority to make their rules—such as defining nexus—and to administer and collect sales taxes themselves. These states are <strong>Alabama, Alaska, Arizona, Colorado</strong> and <strong>Louisiana</strong>. Alaska is a bit of a special case because it has no statewide sales tax, but local jurisdictions can independently levy and collect sales tax according to their own rules.</p>
<p>These are the states in which home rule really <a href="https://www.avalara.com/learn/videos/how-home-rule-states-complicate-tax-compliance/" target="_blank">makes a difference to businesses that collect sales tax</a>. Not all jurisdictions within these states opt to administer their own sales taxes, but those localities that do can amount to their own separate sales tax governments.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">Different definitions</span></h2>
<p>It’s important for small businesses to keep in mind that in home rule states, each locality may define nexus in its own way, as well as requiring its own separate registration, filing and payment process. So what you know about other states, or even what you know about that particular state, may not apply to all the localities with which you do business within the state.</p>
<p>Take, Colorado, for example. It’s the most complex home rule state, with 70 cities that make their own sales tax rules.</p>
<p>If your company is based in Denver, a home rule city, you’ll have nexus in Denver as well as in the state of Colorado. So if you sell something to a customer in Denver, you will need to charge the Denver sales tax, as well as the state tax. While both taxes will be collected in one amount all at once during the transaction, you will need to report and remit the two different tax amounts separately — the city tax to Denver and the state tax to Colorado.</p>
<p>However, if you sell to a customer in Boulder, another home rule city, you will charge state sales tax because you have state nexus, but you will only charge Boulder sales tax on that transaction if you have nexus in Boulder—as Boulder defines it. If you do have nexus in Boulder, you will need to collect Boulder sales tax and state sales tax and remit them separately.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">Trouble at home</span></h2>
<p>In a home rule state with several different jurisdictions and different rules for each, it’s easy to collect sales tax incorrectly, with a number of potential negative consequences.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">Overcollection</span></h2>
<p>One of the biggest risks in home rule states is that of over collecting sales tax. If you assume that because you have nexus in a home rule state, you have nexus in all its localities, you could end up collecting sales tax in places where it’s not actually required. This can expose you to scenarios that are particularly unwelcome to small businesses.</p>
<p>For example, if you’re collecting sales tax for a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction may assume that you have intentionally established business there. This could lead that jurisdiction requiring you to get licenses and perhaps even pay more taxes, such as business &amp; occupation taxes. Proving that you don’t have to follow those regulations because you don’t actually have nexus can take valuable time and resources that are in limited supply for many small businesses.</p>
<p>Overcollection certainly doesn’t make customers happy, either. While providing a poor customer experience is bad enough, what’s even worse is the risk of customer lawsuits over collecting too much sales tax. While larger companies may find such legal battles annoying, having to fight such a lawsuit can be devastating for a small business.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">Undercollection</span></h2>
<p>Undercollecting in home rule states can also be a problem. As in non-home rule states, undercollecting sales tax can expose you to the risk of an audit—something no small business wants to undergo—as well a potentially being required to pay back any owed amount, plus penalties and fees.</p>
<p>Audits by local jurisdictions can present some unique challenges. Even in the same state, each locality may have its own audit rules and process. For example, in Colorado, you could theoretically be audited by several different localities, plus the state, and undergo entirely procedures in each case. In non-home rule states, a single state audit would also cover any localities that may be involved.</p>
<p>And in home rule states Colorado, Louisiana and Alabama, local governments can hire their own private tax auditors. These private companies may have more resources and motivation than cash-strapped government auditors to find businesses that are potentially undercollecting.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">Third-party complications</span></h2>
<p>If you don’t have a physical presence in a home-rule locality, you generally won’t have nexus there and do not have to collect sales taxes for transactions with customers based there. However, if you use a third-party service—such as Fulfillment by Amazon (FBA)—to distribute goods to remote buyers, you may have nexus in the place where Amazon stores those goods for you and not even know it.</p>
<p>In Arizona, for example, if you have goods stored and shipped from an Amazon fulfillment center in Phoenix, you would have nexus in Phoenix, which is a home rule city, as well as in Arizona. Since Arizona state sales tax is based on the origin of the shipment rather than the destination, you would be required to collect the local Phoenix sales tax on those transactions, along with the state sales tax, to be remitted separately.</p>
<p>However, Arizona has passed legislation that puts more restrictions on how cities can administer sales tax and starting in 2017; there will <a href="https://www.azdor.gov/TPTSimplification/About.aspx" target="_blank">no longer be separate local sales tax returns in Arizona</a>.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #ff5301">A simple solution</span></h2>
<p>If you have sales tax obligation in home rule states, sales tax automation can be a useful solution. Avalara AvaTax easily integrates with PrestaShop and automatically calculates the right rates for both state and local taxes, wherever you might be doing business. In addition, AvaTax offers affordable plans designed especially for small businesses to help you make sure you’re getting sales taxes done right. <a href="https://www.avalara.com/integrations/prestashop/" target="_blank">Learn more here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/small-business-guide-home-rule-sales-tax/">The Small business guide to home rule and sales tax</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/small-business-guide-home-rule-sales-tax/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Outdated Designs You Need to Remove At Once from your Website</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-outdated-designs-need-remove-website/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-outdated-designs-need-remove-website/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 08:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21870</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Back in the day, websites captured users’ attention by using cool animation and effects. It’s 2016, and these tricks don’t work anymore. The users of today are web-savvy and have a short attention span due to their fast-paced lives. So, you’ve got a mere 15 seconds to grab their interest to your website. Based on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-outdated-designs-need-remove-website/">6 Outdated Designs You Need to Remove At Once from your Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back in the day, websites captured users’ attention by using cool animation and effects. It’s 2016, and these tricks don’t work anymore.</p>
<p>The users of today are web-savvy and have a short attention span due to their fast-paced lives. So, you’ve got a mere 15 seconds to grab their interest to your website. Based on this evolution, new web design trends focus on providing a better experience that won’t infuriate the users and make them exit your site.</p>
<p><span id="more-21870"></span></p>
<p>So, whether your website is a few years old, or you need tips on what you shouldn’t do as a web designer, here are 6 outdated web design trends that you need to get rid of right now.</p>
<h2 style="color: #555c8a">1. Unrealistic stock images</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21871" alt="1 outdated" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/1-outdated.jpg" width="568" height="370" /></p>
<p>Stock images are a useful way to represent ideas, but here’s the problem with it &#8211; some websites resort to clichéd stock images and take it beyond the necessary limit.</p>
<p>As a result, there are many websites plastered with the same old unrealistic, bad stock images of happy employees and eerie looking salespeople talking on headphones.</p>
<p>Images are incorporated to provide credibility, but stock images do just the opposite. Companies have used stock photos so excessively that users tend to remember these images. And every time they come across just another clichéd image of successful businessmen dressed in professional attire, they are immediately put off and tend to build a negative association towards your website.</p>
<p>So if you want to build credibility for your company, invest in a professional photographer. If your budget doesn’t allow for it, try to include relevant stock images instead of the clichéd ones.</p>
<h2 style="color: #555c8a">2. Flash introduction</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21872" alt="2 outdated" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/2-outdated.jpg" width="568" height="370" /></p>
<p>Abode Flash is a development platform for creating web-based animations and games. While they were extensively popular a few years ago, they are an absolute no-no right now.</p>
<p>Flash-based websites take too long to load, are incompatible with smartphones, and have specific system requirements – in short; they are an unnecessary display of your creativity which drives away your users. Plus, it’s not Google-friendly and is likely to hinder your search engine optimization efforts.</p>
<h2 style="color: #555c8a">3. Pop-ups</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21873" alt="3 outdated" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/3-outdated.jpg" width="568" height="370" /></p>
<p>These are the most frustrating element of a website. Whether it’s an e-mail registration, newsletter sign-up or any other kind of promotional content, pop-ups are infuriating and can drive away your users’ interests.</p>
<p>While many marketers may argue otherwise, users come to your website to gather information and pop-ups are a complete hindrance for them. Moreover, in most cases, pop-ups are difficult to close on smartphones.</p>
<p>If you want to promote your newsletter or gain e-mail contacts, try to use other areas of the website and persuade users to sign up with lead magnets.</p>
<h2 style="color: #555c8a">4. Carousel Sliders</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21874" alt="4 outdated" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/4-outdated.jpg" width="590" height="216" /></p>
<p>Carousel sliders were a raging trend, but the designers of today will tell you otherwise. Usually, you get only mere seconds to capture your visitors’ interest, and if you have important information on your 3rd or last carousel image, then your visitor are sure to miss it.</p>
<p>Direct your visitor’s attention with one powerful image and place appropriate content to explain your message.</p>
<h2 style="color: #555c8a">5. Outdated fonts</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21875" alt="5 outdated" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/5-outdated.jpg" width="568" height="370" /></p>
<p>Trends affect the font style too. So if you don’t want your website to have 2000’s vibes, then steer clear of fonts such as Comic Sans, Times New Roman and other Cursive fonts. Also, bevel and emboss effect are a strict no-no. (Bevel and emboss is a Photoshop effect used to give a three-dimensional effect.)</p>
<p>Stick to flat designs, vector elements and clean interface. Also, it’s best to use a maximum of three fonts for your entire website.</p>
<h2 style="color: #555c8a">6. Skeuomorphic design</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21876" alt="6 outdated" src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/06/6-outdated.jpg" width="568" height="370" /></p>
<p>Skeuomorphic design refers to elements based on real-life items. For example, an online book store resembling the bookshelves at an actual store; refer to skeuomorphic designs. Popularized by iPhone, skeuomorphic designs are outdated right now. The trend of today is flat and simplistic designs. If you have drop shadows and gradient effects, now is the time to opt out of these glossy designs.</p>
<p>Do you have more than 2 of these outdated design elements? It’s time to start thinking about a new website design. Get a second opinion by contacting one of our web agencies. Have other design trends you’re tired of seeing? Share your thoughts in the comments below.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>About the author:</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/bronze/shamlatech">SHAMLATECH</a> is a Global Enterprise Service Agency serving happy clients over the past 8 years in the industry. The services include web and eCommerce development, Mobile application development and Digital Marketing.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-outdated-designs-need-remove-website/">6 Outdated Designs You Need to Remove At Once from your Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-outdated-designs-need-remove-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nine Essential Features of an Online Fashion and Accessories Store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nine-essential-features-online-fashion-accessories-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nine-essential-features-online-fashion-accessories-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 13:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cécile Dubouis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21849</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you run a fashion-oriented ecommerce business, then you’re already aware of the particular needs and challenges of selling clothes, shoes and accessories online: mobile accessibility, simple and fluid navigation and attractiveness are just the beginning. Here at PrestaShop we’ve put together a list of the best modules for your online store so you can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nine-essential-features-online-fashion-accessories-store/">The Nine Essential Features of an Online Fashion and Accessories Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you run a fashion-oriented ecommerce business, then you’re already aware of the particular needs and challenges of selling clothes, shoes and accessories online: mobile accessibility, simple and fluid navigation and attractiveness are just the beginning.</p>
<p>Here at PrestaShop we’ve put together a list of the best modules for your online store so you can perform stronger in every aspect of your business. Adopt these e-commerce best practices to optimize your fashion store!</p>
<p><span id="more-21849"></span></p>
<h2>User-friendly navigation</h2>
<p><strong>Responsive web design</strong><br />
When shopping for fashion, 45-60% of customers use a mobile device, either to browse before going to a store, or to make purchases directly. Don&#8217;t miss out on their business!<br />
Choose a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/47-fashion-shoes-templates" target="_blank">responsive design template</a> for these potential customers.</p>
<p><em><strong>Tip:</strong> use filters to choose the style of your store&#8217;s design (clean effect, minimalist, modern, etc.)</em></p>
<p><strong>Infinite scrolling</strong><br />
Just like the big fashion brands, let your customers view your collection without having to switch pages constantly. Reduce the number of clicks and ease navigation in order to hold your customers&#8217; attention on your products—and only your products—with an <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/17439-infinite-scroll-premium.html" target="_blank">infinite scroll</a> feature.</p>
<p><strong>Show products in different colors</strong><br />
Are your products available in different colors? Improve your category pages by showing every version of your products. For example, let&#8217;s say a visitor is looking for a red dress. With a glance at a category page, she can find just what she wants. Without this feature, navigating gets complicated. The visitor must click on every dress to see if it is available in red. You must avoid discouraging the visitor (who may leave your site) at all costs by <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/20451-products-by-attributes.html" target="_blank">displaying all your products by range</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Filters, facets and brands</strong><br />
It is simple and quick for your users to select filters (product type, size, color, etc.) in order to see only the products they want that are available in the store. To offer this feature on your site, all you need to do is use <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/510-search-filters" target="_blank">filter tools, and faceted search and navigation</a>.<br />
Are you a reseller? Don&#8217;t forget to let your users <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/512-brands-manufacturers" target="_blank">navigate by brand</a> to optimize your conversions.</p>
<p><em><strong>Expert tip:</strong> MODZ increased its conversion rate by 37% and its return visit rate by 25% by implementing search filters to guide users directly towards items in their size.</em></p>
<h2>Customer Satisfaction and Reduced Product Returns</h2>
<p><strong>Size Guide</strong><br />
90% of online stores do this. No matter whether you sell clothes, underwear, jewelry or belts, offer a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/22779-size-guide.html" target="_blank">size guide</a>. This helps you guide your customers to the products that fit them, optimizing client satisfaction, and in particular reducing the need for after-sales service.</p>
<p><strong>Product Composition</strong><br />
Be sure to clearly show the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/19273-compositions-and-materials.html" target="_blank">product composition</a>, materials used, and even washing instructions for the fabric. There are many reasons to show this information, such as quality assurance of your products and allergies to certain materials, among others, but two in particular stand out:</p>
<ul>
<li>The more detailed your product pages are, the fewer product returns you will have;</li>
<li>A comprehensive page optimizes your natural SEO.</li>
</ul>
<p>All the more reason to take advantage of it!</p>
<h2>Encouraging purchases</h2>
<p><strong>Visuals</strong><br />
All customers want to see, touch and try before buying. In e-commerce, seeing has replaced touching. So it&#8217;s essential to provide:<br />
high-quality visuals (at least two per product)<br />
<a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/1914-magic-zoom-plus.html" target="_blank">zoom views</a> to better display products&#8217; materials and colors.</p>
<p><em><strong>Expert tip:</strong> Etam saw its online sales grow by 15% after placing visuals of lingerie sets being modeled on the online category pages. Clients now had a better view of the product and were encouraged to click on the product page.</em></p>
<p><strong>Labels and badges to promote your products</strong><br />
&#8220;Best Seller&#8221;, &#8220;Favorite&#8221;, &#8220;Special Offer&#8221;, &#8220;Premium Delivery&#8221;&#8230; By adding <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/20844-product-label.html" target="_blank">badges tailored to your products</a> you capture your visitors&#8217; full attention right from your store&#8217;s home page.<br />
These labels also let you emphasize information on your product pages about materials used (&#8220;100% cotton&#8221;, &#8220;solid gold&#8221;, etc.) or the manufacturing country.</p>
<p><strong>Lookbook</strong><br />
Inspire your customers by showing them an outfit that uses a combination of products.<br />
A <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/20150-lookbook-product-scenes.html" target="_blank">lookbook</a> encourages your customers not just to make a purchase, but also to fill up the average shopping basket, since they choose several items instead of just one.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nine-essential-features-online-fashion-accessories-store/">The Nine Essential Features of an Online Fashion and Accessories Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/nine-essential-features-online-fashion-accessories-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Attract clients when launching an online business:  Interview with Rachel Bouchon of Atelieramour.com</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/attract-clients-launching-online-business-interview-wth-rachel-bouchon-atelieramour-com/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/attract-clients-launching-online-business-interview-wth-rachel-bouchon-atelieramour-com/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 08:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[mvalenza]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21812</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Bouchon turned her experience in the lingerie industry into a successful online business: www.atelier-amour.com is an innovative company that takes the challenge out of buying lingerie as a gift or as a personal treat. In today’s interview, Rachel shares her advice for laying the groundwork for a successful website in order to attract customers from [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/attract-clients-launching-online-business-interview-wth-rachel-bouchon-atelieramour-com/">Attract clients when launching an online business:  Interview with Rachel Bouchon of Atelieramour.com</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rachel Bouchon turned her experience in the lingerie industry into a successful online business: www.atelier-amour.com is an innovative company that takes the challenge out of buying lingerie as a gift or as a personal treat. In today’s interview, Rachel shares her advice for laying the groundwork for a successful website in order to attract customers from the very beginning.<br />
<span id="more-21812"></span></p>
<div class="g-ytsubscribe col-centered text-center" data-channelid="UCqDSbqSbkboMBARlYrhNa7g" data-layout="full" data-count="default"></div>
<p><iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-dFjWdtpx3U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn" style="background-color: #cd201f; border: 1px solid #b31217; border-bottom: 3px solid #b31217; margin: 20px 0 0; color: #fff;" href="https://www.youtube.com/user/prestashop?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=Youtube-launch&amp;utm_content=atelieramour" target="_blank"><i class="fa fa-youtube-play"></i> Watch more videos</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/attract-clients-launching-online-business-interview-wth-rachel-bouchon-atelieramour-com/">Attract clients when launching an online business:  Interview with Rachel Bouchon of Atelieramour.com</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/attract-clients-launching-online-business-interview-wth-rachel-bouchon-atelieramour-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
